Finding aid for the Kotaro Suto Papers, ca. 1905-1965 LSC.2010.37
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kotaro Suto Papers
ca. 1905-1965
UCLA Library Special Collections
Suto, Kotaro
LSC.2010.37
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes and 1 oversize box)
Kotaro Suto was born circa 1883 in Kanagawa Prefecture, Japan. He came to the United States in 1900 and relocated to Miami Beach, Florida, ca. 1916. He married Masa Suto in 1921. Mr. Suto worked for Miami pioneer developer Carl Fisher before starting his own nursery business. This collection contains clippings about the Sutos (mostly from Miami sources), photographs and snapshots of the Sutos, records and correspondence related to Suto's nursery, and correspondence and other records related to the Suto's donations to various charitable organizations. It also includes clippings on Fisher. Materials in this collection are primarily in English, with some in Japanese.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942338413606533
Biography
Kotaro Suto was born circa 1883 in Kanagawa Prefecture. He came to the United States in 1900 and relocated to Miami Beach, Florida, about 1916. He married Masa Suto in 1921 and worked for Miami pioneer developer, Carl Fisher, before starting his own nursery business. Mr. Suto was given many commendations and honors for his active participation in and devotion to the city of Miami. Kotaro and Masa, known as Papa and Mama, became United States citizens in 1958. Kotaro died in 1963.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, clippings, business records, and photographs related to the life of Kotaro Suto and his wife Masa Suto. Includes clippings about the Sutos mostly from Miami sources, photographs and snapshots of the Sutos, records and correspondence related to Suto's nursery, and correspondence and other records related to the Suto's donations to various charitable organizations. Also includes clippings on Carl G. Fisher, Miami pioneer.
Materials in this collection are primarily in English, with some in Japanese.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence and newspaper clippings (Box 141).
Business records and correspondence, photographs, and miscellany (Box 142).
Oversize photographs.
Related Material
Kotaro Suto Papers (Collection 483). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library.
Japanese American Research Project - Fading Footsteps of the Issei (Collection 2010). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library.
Clippings.; Correspondence.; Japanese Americans -- Florida -- Miami -- Archival resources.; Nursery dealers -- Florida -- Miami -- Archival resources.; Nursery growers -- Florida -- Miami -- Archival resources.; Japanese American Research Project (University of California, Los Angeles); Sut, Ktar--Archives.; Suto, Masa.
- Suto Papers, ca. 1905-1965; 2.0 linear ft.
  - Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings, 0.5 linear ft.
    - Correspondence exchanged between the Japanese American Research Project (JARP) and Mrs. Kotaro Suto and her lawyer, F.R. Stanton., May 1964-November 1965; (9 items) (Box 141, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      re the donation of the Suto papers to the project.
    - Newspaper clippings on the Suts., January 1953-October 1965; (59 items) (Box 141, Folder 2)
      Mostly from local English language press.
    - Magazine articles on the Suts., 1953-1954 (Box 141, Folder 3)
      - "Ben Funk and James Monahan, Happy Where Heart Is", Reader's Digest., June 1954; (pp. 1-4) (Box 141, Folder 3)
      - "Miami Beach says goodbye to pioneer Suto", Scene., April 1953; (pp. 17-19) (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - Suto Correspondence., September 1929-May 1963; (356 pieces) (Box 141, Folder 4-7)
    - Various business licenses of the Suto Nursery, Miami, Florida., 1937-1953; (21 pieces) (Box 141, Folder 8)
  - Business Records and Correspondence, Photographs and Miscellany, 1.5 linear ft.
    - Business correspondence on the importation of orchid plants., December 1938-August 1949; (84 pieces) (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - Special permits to import plants, United States Department of Agriculture and its instruction sheets on the importation of plants., 1938-1941 & 1954; (50 pieces) (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - Letters of recommendation for Sut., April-May 1920; (3 pieces) (Box 142, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous papers re property deeds., 1935 & 1949-1950; (11 pieces) (Box 142, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and other records re the Suts' donations to various charitable organizations., 1932-1953; (124 pieces) (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Photographs and snapshots of the Suts., 1914-1965; (99 pieces) (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous items., 1943-1945; (11 pieces) (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings on the late Carl G. Fisher, Sut's employer and friend., July 1939; (9 pieces) (Box 142, Folder 8)
    - Oversize photographs., ca. 1905-ca. 1953; (5 pieces) (Box 723)